hey quick editor note uh before we get
into this episode so uh last week the
Apple Vision Pro uh came out and I asked
uh my friends Devon Davies and Christian
seelig if they wanted to to attempt to
do a different kind of episode of launch
than I've done before um we we wanted to
do a video episode where we actually you
know are inside of the uh the vision
Pros uh as our weird Persona things um
and kind of talk about the launch of
this new platform and their two apps
that kind of went with it and had some
success already um so that's what we did
it was genuinely really fun but as
you'll hear uh there's kind of a couple
technical snafus uh lost recordings the
video cut out at one point so you know
if there's some weird stuff uh that's
why and also if you're listening to this
like you normally do in your podcast
feed um there is a video version on
YouTube I'll include uh the link to the
YouTube page and the show notes of
course
um but if you're interested in that
that'll be linked there it'll be the
same audio either way which means the
audio will also be a lot less edited
than normal because uh I can't get away
with nearly as many Cuts or tightening
things up in video form as I can with
audio so uh there's all my excuses out
of the way let's get to the
show Welcome to launched I'm Charlie
Chapman and today I'm excited to bring
you Devon Davies the developer behind
the cooking app Crouton and Christian
seelake the developer behind the vision
OS YouTube app
Juno
Devin Christian welcome to the show hey
yay so uh all right we just got right
off the bat we we went ahead and knocked
out the the awkwardness that is going to
be this we just spent how long has it
been like 30 minutes no it's been like
50 minutes uh that we've spent
trying to get this set up and I'm at
least about 50% sure that this is
actually being recorded so so we'll see
how this actually goes it's been the
best period of My Life by
far I'm just happy to be here all right
well um I'll try to keep us on the rails
as best as I can so uh the idea here is
both of you have actually been on this
show before Christian you were the like
the second person I ever had on oh wow I
didn't realize that yeah yeah it was
kind it was during that crazy like
original a week um and Devon you were on
it was last year right yeah not long
before you canceled it
yeah you say that like they're related
somehow I could never pop it you
know um but no like my thought here was
uh all three of us obviously as anybody
can see we all have uh the vision Os or
sorry the vision Apple Vision Pro as
it's called um and all three three of us
though you two more so than me uh have
actually developed apps for it we were
there on day one um Devin you had
Crouton your cooking app that already
existed for um all the other Apple
platforms you you spent a very long time
uh making it like truly native for the
platform and making like a a cooking
experience
right and then yeah oh sorry go ahead oh
I was going to say I feel like um cuz
the product have been rumored for so
long there's kind of a lot of time
before it even launched to kind of
ideate on what it might be like so yeah
I think it was great to be able to like
jump into it kind of running in a way
and then Christian uh you you weren't
necessarily I I don't think you were
really planning the app that you came
out with Juno until relatively recently
whenever it came out that there was not
going to be a native YouTube app is that
right yeah yeah definitely not as or
organized as Devon because man I
remember like at WWDC like I think like
the day after you were like mocking up
stuff in sketch somehow before that SDK
came out so yeah no I wasn't anything
like that um I think the YouTube lack of
a YouTube announcement came out and I
was like oh that sucks and I was like oh
man oh wait I'm an app developer like
maybe I could maybe I could do something
there and then yeah it was a quick dash
for a week and managed to put something
together I think we kind of and then
mine was very much also the weak thing
but with even less time and it's not
even necessarily worth talking about so
we probably really won't but I think we
kind of represent the the different
approaches that developers have taken to
the platform um and both of you have had
very interesting experiences post launch
so I think I think I mean I know there's
like a bajillion different pieces of
content related to this new platform
already but I I think we can kind of
bring an interesting perspective in here
so that was that was kind of the idea
behind the show we'll see how it
actually ends up
going so to start out I want to like uh
Devon I want to like let you talk
through sort of the story of of not
Crouton the whole app if whoa I just
sent my notes flying across the room uh
okay literally yeah yeah knocked over my
TV um no uh so we've talked about
obviously Crouton the app already on the
show so if somebody's interested in that
they should go listen to that episode
but since the announcement last summer
um to Last Friday which is like four
days ago as we record um I just want to
talk through the story of like how you
built spatial Computing or whatever you
want to call that into uh into
Crouton yeah totally I feel like I
should apologize off the bat as well for
now I'm watching this for the fact that
my mouth doesn't close all the
Way's I have to say everybody's reaction
to your persona in particular has always
been like oh that's pretty good I think
I think you have had the best one of all
of them I've seen but you're you're
self-conscious about the mouth not Clos
which is
pretty I think I'll just opt for keeping
it very wide open so there's no
[Laughter]
just but yeah so Crouton um yeah I guess
say Christian said like once the um
after d the
keynote uh there wasn't really like the
didn't drop straight away there was like
a couple of days there um before it came
out um but I kind of was pretty excited
about it and wanted to start think about
how Crouton might look so I spend a bit
of time in sketch just sort of trying to
use the vision OS design Paradigm and
mock up a few things um it is
interesting actually like trying to use
those tools that were built for kind of
iOS design then trying to do things like
the like these glass backgrounds oh yeah
like in sketch yeah you run into some
limitations pretty quick and laptop
definitely gets a bit warmer trying to
render so many like blur yeah glass
Textures in P in particular it kind of
struggles with right yeah which is weird
because didn't like Windows Vista do
that fascinating like did it so well too
yeah yeah they must head of the curve
that Vista but was your was your sketch
markups like anywhere close to what you
ended up
shipping uh I mean the rough idea was
there I think the okay I mean the basic
concept of cooking in AR has kind of
been I guess one of like the maybe the
poster Childs of of VR stuff for a while
of just like placing stuff in the
kitchen so there's definitely some ideas
that other people have had um um that
then I could sort of draw on and add a
few things in as well so um I think it's
pretty much the same just the designs
changed a bit as I've obviously then
going from sketch and actually using
Swift UI to build the things it's much
easier cuz you just get the glass
backgrounds for free in the simulator
and you have to spend ages adding the
extra like Reflections and the corners
and things outside of the design itself
though like what were the main obviously
putting timers sitting over your pot
that's you're running a timer on like
that's the obvious like poster child
sort of example but there's other things
that you did so like what are the what
are the spatial elements that you
brought in to the app to make it
sing yeah well I think even the big one
for me is just having your um the recipe
steps and the ingredients so big and
obvious like if you have a recipe book
or even the iPad I'm running Crouton if
you cross the other side of the room you
can't read it at all so if you head to
the pantry to get some ingredients or
something like that you then forget the
ingredients you went for maybe that's
just me you got to go back the book
whereas if you can just turn around and
like just see it pretty much as big from
the other side of the room I think
that's a big a big saving um in time
yeah that's an example I all I've cooked
with it so far uh just because my kids
have been sick so I haven't actually
been like properly cooking uh in the
last two days but I did make some cereal
with it uh which was a pretty intense
process but even there I noticed exactly
what you said which is like one of the
nice things is that you can have your
ingredients with you all the time but
was the recipe less Long oh you know
there's a lot there's a lot going on
when I make Cheerios
Christian but
like uh but like it everything's really
anchored in physical space which is cool
but that means that you sort of almost
end up with the same negative which is
like if I walk over to the cupboard I
have to like lean my head back to see
where I left the ingredients list to see
it now it's easier because it's gigantic
and it's floating in my space but it
would be cool if uh like a future API
they give us which is like you can pin
something to yourself if that makes
sense so it like follows you
around yeah I think something like that
would be interesting it's hard to know
how that would work with with multiple
apps running like if you end up with
like 10 Windows pinned to you or like
who which app gets to control what gets
pinned where is that like a system
decision or does the user do it yeah it
feels like something you should just be
able to control like it's a it's a I
almost said springboard but whatever the
the framework is for the platform itself
like I should have like a floating list
of Windows I can like put down at the
bottom of my view or something that kind
of like follow me around or something
like that you should into the
window yeah yeah I was just thinking you
could also just make it so like whatever
was there last if if there's no room it
just gets kicked out and the most recent
one wins um yeah like only one thing can
be there at a time yeah yeah or
something just like an IOS app or
something something yeah cuz I've been
on FaceTime calls where I've been
walking through my house uh and I like
grab I'm being very careful not to
actually do the gesture I'm I like grab
the window and I carry you know my mom
around the house with me uh which sort
of felt at first it felt cool and then
I'm like it's kind of the same as my
phone though at that point like I'm
holding it uh I should be able to just
say like I want this to be with me and
it just kind of hovers around with me
right and I think for a cooking app or
something cuz like you can you can hold
the button to reenter your view but then
that would take all your kitchen timers
and pull them off of the thing that you
stuck them to which would also kind of
undo that that use
case yeah you so you can pin things to
users now as well but you have to do it
in the immersive mode which means only
your app can be running and I think part
of the appeal of Crouton too is that you
might have other things going like a
video and um such like so if you didn't
had to like close everything just to
cook I feel like maybe be less uh
inclined to use Vision profit cooking
yeah okay I see what you're saying so an
immersive app can pin things to the
person so those apis do exist yeah yeah
yeah the wheels really come off I don't
know if that's the saying but you can do
a lot more in immersive mode than you
can in like you say whale or wheel
wheels that's that's the NOA sco the
whales um but yeah yeah you can do so
much more in immersive mode but it's
tricky because you get that balance of
like should I kick everyone else out of
the party yeah yeah yeah cuz I think for
YouTube could definitely work yeah
that's what I was thinking like if you
were watching a YouTube video and you
wanted to pin it to your head you're
probably not like have 700 other things
going on like if you're walking around
the house vacuuming or something but
yeah I don't know it would be cool for
like 2.0 or something yeah it feels like
the type of thing that developers should
be able to control but maybe that does
make sense in immersive mode but then
the window system itself should let you
just pin a window to
yourself yeah maybe not even at the app
level yeah yeah exactly it's kind of
just like uh an OS feature of like like
a menu bar app or whatever where it's
like I want these to exist in a space
outside of the rest of my my like
spatial windows or whatever you want to
call that right yeah and we're going to
get in such a fun developer uh position
where it's like how you had like pre-
dark mode everyone had dark mode in
their apps and then the actual API
like oh god I've gots to support this
indepently of the OS like what I do I
was just talking to somebody about this
I was like I think the thing that's
super exciting about this is we haven't
had an
immature platform from Apple in a while
I mean I guess Apple watch kind of but
like at least I haven't played around in
that space the same way it was still
like 10 years ago yeah there's so much
loow hanging fruit that like every
dubdub there can be a bunch of small
things that they do that all of us kind
of gasp like ah you know I can uh the
keyboard works or uh what's the one oh
like I can reorder my apps on my home
screen like everybody will be like yes
finally or you can bring the the main
window back to the foreground when you
close all your second Windows yeah yeah
that's one that might be interesting in
this conversation too like baby stamps
something developers have been fighting
every developer it seems like building a
vision OS app has sort of run into is
what do you do if you open multiple
windows and then you close your main
window and there isn't like a OS
Paradigm for that so everybody's kind of
like making their own solution for that
like adding a home button or something
like what did you do Devon because you
have that problem
right uh at the moment I've just
neglected
it um that's what I was hoping your
answer would
be I I'm doing a few different things in
different windows and there's nothing
consistent I'm just hoping that we'll
get like a 1. One release
yeah I wonder what do you think dubdub
is going to be I'm I've basically thrown
out my whole plan here and we're just
going to keep talking uh but like dubdub
this year uh is like only what four
months or something into the platform
but do you think we'll get like a proper
new release or will it be like a
1. five or something like that like up
until you said how there's so many low
hanging fruit I was like no chance
there's going to be like Vision OS 2.0
AT dubdub even even though that's when
they normally get previewed but now
you're I'm like yeah they could just
nail out like 20 really obvious
hopefully quick features and everyone
would be like yeah that's a 2.0 like
yeah well and like when do you think
they locked this version like I bet it
was earlier than even normal because of
hardware and stuff I could see or maybe
it's the opposite I don't know yeah I
was going to say I could see it being
way earlier than normal or like they
were coding until like last
week yeah yeah so it's it's I don't know
I bet you though like everything there's
like feature lock right so like I'm sure
the stuff that is in it they were
probably up until the last minute
getting bugs ironed out but I bet
there's a lot of things that they cut
from V1 that are like close to or maybe
they are ready to go now but they had to
make that choice in November or earlier
September or something that's a good
question I feel like they'd want to sh a
2.0 way you moved your head it looked
like your head just like your neck just
snapped oh no it did in real life that
that's actually pretty accurate
ofical
emergency you hear sirens don't be
alarmed yeah to be fair we wouldn't know
if you're on the way to the hospital or
not just no you're doing this fromit
from the back of see my head bouncing
from the CPR it
my uh so okay so you like I said that
kind of broke my whole thing here but
like uh so we talked about like yeah the
idea of cooking with there's a couple
like very VR features though that you
added too right Devon like there's like
a measuring like a 3D measuring
thing yeah so I I don't know about you
but often in like a recipe when it says
get like a 12 x 12 in tray I mean it
just don't really convert for me anyway
but you I read that and just have no
idea what it means so I just grab a tray
and hope for the best um so I thought it
would be cool to be able to actually
visualize what that size is and then
hopefully by looking at it you can think
oh yeah I've got you know like a
casserole dish that's pretty close to
that oh yeah for baking that makes I'm
understanding yeah or like any often
recip is just I don't know like to tell
you what size to use um so you can just
um tap on it in the recipe um just like
look and pinch and then it um will open
up like a volumetric space with the the
size essentially so you just pop that on
the bench and then um go grab what you
need does that let you cuz I haven't
tried that one yet does that
like is there an affordance for placing
something on the table itself or is it
kind of like some guess workor because
i' I've noticed I've struggled with that
with some of the games I've wanted to
put it on my you know coffee table and
like there is no like kind of snapping
two like I was
expecting yeah I think uh there's it
definitely doesn't snap to it but you
get the shadow which helps a little bit
you can sort of see when it connects if
you want to do any kind of pinning it's
pretty similar to the person we have to
be in the immersive mode which then you
could sort of you could detect I think
the the bech top um and pin directly it
feels like it's another one of those
things where it's it feels like the the
like OS windowing system
should have like if you're really close
to an edge cuz it detects it obviously
because it's putting the shadow there if
it just kind of would snap in to be like
yeah I'm locking it into that spot but
maybe it's not quite good enough that
they almost don't want to encourage you
to do that I don't know I don't have you
played Fruit Ninja it's yeah cuz that
has the floor stuff and works I had
fruit landing on the couch next to me
like bouncing off the cushions and it
was very convincing oh I haven't I I was
in like the most open part of my room
you got to go somewhere messy and then
well it was messy but not there wasn't
any big furniture oh that's interesting
yeah I'll have to try
that so okay so that that was Crouton
you did um I know we I don't know all of
us did a lab I don't know if any of us
are technically allowed to talk about it
or not but just in a like helpful not
helpful that's more or less the
granularity I'm asking for here did you
feel like the labs were useful for you
Devon while you were building this
out uh yeah definitely I the similar
thing to like um building iaps I think
if you build something in the simulator
for an IAP you often then run it on your
phone and you're like whoa these buttons
are like all the wrong size um this is
not usable and so yeah I think
definitely going to a lab makes a pretty
difference to just eying out a few
things that you kind of Miss do we know
are they going to continue doing those
like I think so like yeah that's what I
was thinking CU they were doing them
like even a week before or something and
I kind of had the thought like a lot of
developers probably can't afford to buy
one of these but like if they live in
one of the you know blessed places uh
being able to go to a lab would still be
super useful cuz yeah that was my
experience too Devon like especially
with the audio stuff it just literally
Works different uh than it does on real
device uh so I couldn't even test a lot
of my stuff until you know it actually I
actually got one of these and what about
you Christian what you did you do a lab
after you started Juno or was it all
before no it was it was I wanted to play
around with pixel Pals at the time um
and so it wasn't too helpful for Juno
just because I hadn't conceived it yet
but um it it was definitely helpful for
that and just kind of figuring out like
how it works as a as a paradigm I guess
like the like you play around with an
iPad simulator and even if you don't
have an iPad you're like okay it's a 2d
rectangle like I kind of got the gist of
it even though like absolutely running
it on device is a million times more
helpful but like with this I found it
Amplified it even further like you're
like so so many things you're like oh
that'll work well like doesn't work at
all um so yeah I found it I found it
super helpful just in kind of like
recalibrating your expectations like as
how the device works and yeah I
definitely recommend going if you're
like um if you have the means to like
the calculus is tricky because for me it
was like it was on the same Coast as me
but I still had to like leave Canada and
go to New York and it was like you do
the math and you're like like three of
those maybe and it would pay for the
Vision Pro and you're like so like
you've got people like Emanuel who makes
card pointers who I think like lived at
the labs because it was probably like
next door to him it was really easy to
get to yeah yeah and it's like that then
it's a no-brainer for you um like if
it's just if it's an easy access but for
a lot of us it's a little trickier you
did the in-person pickup uh for your
actual device right so does that mean
you did what essentially if you just to
demo what you would do basically like
they were like like do basically like
they were like do you want to demo and
kind of like pushing for like you should
I think it was because like we were also
the first of the day so I think the
employees were kind of like jonesing to
like try out this thing they've probably
been like practicing for days um and no
they were like this is Christian seelake
like yeah yeah yeah no that that that
was definitely definitely heard a lot of
that but it was the washed up Reddit
developer walks into the Apple store but
no it was no there were very good and
they were it was it felt like they were
um like I don't know like you do a
school play and it's the opening night
and they're like okay this is what we've
been practicing for um and they seemed
really excited to do it um and it was
just a really cool demo so um I think I
got the whole whole sheam there was
definitely some like technical glitches
as they figured things out but like it
went incredibly smoothly I thought for
like how it was basically the first time
so in terms of cuz the the reason I ask
is like uh a lot of people maybe can't
get to Cupertino or New York or Sydney
or wherever but like if but more people
have access to an Apple store do you
think doing one of those demos if you're
wanting to develop for this would be
useful or is it a lot more like this is
watching a movie you know which isn't
necessarily helpful as a developer I
guess it depends can you like tell the
Apple employee yeah I'm totally uh
following your demo and then just go off
and likeall X code um cuz does it take
you through any of the default apps at
all like do you do you get the
experience obviously you do get the
experience of looking and tapping but I
just mean the sort of interactive model
that's what super weird they bring You
Through Safari to start um and then you
go into photos and then I think it's
mostly the Apple TV app um so there's
definitely a moment and they have you
rearrange windows so there's definitely
an opportunity to kind of get at home
with the operating system that that I
think is really helpful but um
definitely like similar to the labs make
sure that your Apple store has it
because I went to mine and they were
like we don't sell these in Canada like
what are you doing here don't I thought
you had to sign up for a spot that was
also an issue they said like it it did
not go
well um okay so I guess that's Crouton
so Juno like we kind of touched on it
it's a lot shorter of a story but like
what's the what's the like uh the
impetus for why you made it we already
kind of said they announced there wasn't
a YouTube app but yeah it was basically
just like I watch a lot of YouTube and
like for me the Vision Pro was kind of
like oh this is going to be an awesome
like content consumption device like
having like a massive screen not even if
you're on a plane but just like sitting
in your living room and like I don't
have 120in TV um and I thought that
would be so cool um and I was kind of
like crestf falling that I was like oh
there's not a YouTube app like up until
like 99% of the announcement of the
vision Pro's life I was like this will
be something I'll be able to use and
they kind of dropped that at the last
minute and I was like sh like can I make
this even a little better for myself
because in Apollo I like there was like
and if you go to like hour videos it's
almost all YouTube videos so I had to
build like a somewhat competent YouTube
player um so I had a lot of code that
was kind of like an experience
interfacing with YouTube in some
capacity so I was like oh if even if I
could just take like Apollo's
implementation and make that into a
YouTube app that would be infinitely
better than the website um and
thankfully it was and I and I kind of
used that code as a jumping point it was
able to put together something pretty
quickly that I was like yeah this is at
least a lot better than the website for
a 1.0 and hopefully Beyond I can take it
substantially further even yet so then
so you got that put together pretty
quickly was it like you were using the
actual YouTube API and then making a
like native Swift UI app right it's not
like it's a web rapper it's it's sort of
like a hybrid between both like YouTube
has like um an API in the same way
Reddit had an API um and that you
can you can call he says with sadness
yeah moment of silence Good Times um
yeah where you can call like an endpoint
and a returns Json which is great and
you can even upload videos but there's
no component um to be like can I um
like get the video with this ID to like
show in a in an AV player view
controller or whatever yeah um which is
so it's kind of like you're a little
limited there so I was like okay um what
do I want to do there and with Apollo
funnily enough like I did it's it's
effectively a web rapper and that
YouTube gives you like this this video
player element and then you can call a
bunch of JavaScript methods to interface
with it so you can call like pause video
doplay video you know do enable
subtitles or whatever um and you get
basically like this programmatic access
to the underlying video player even if
you don't get the actual video file so
you can't do like cool stuff like airpl
or like download the video um but you
can programmatically interface with the
video so you can put like native
controls up um on top of this like web
layer and interface with it directly so
you kind of get like something that's
substantially better than just a web
view um but not quite as good as a fully
native view um and that that was kind of
the basis for it and that was how Apollo
operated and it worked convincingly
enough that I was pretty happy with it
um so that that was kind of the where I
was approaching it from if you can
believe it I am actually familiar with
those apis because I built a uh I built
a a video player inside of the Windows 8
tablet app for the grand old oery uh way
back in the day for the
what do you think it still works the
grand old opery uh it's like is that
like an opera uh no it's like a country
music music uh Hall in
Nashville it's where like the music
scene I think like kind of spur out of
Music came from and you built like an
them it's where all music came from yes
amazing uh it's kind of incredible yeah
but you like built their but yeah yeah
it was whenever I was doing the like
Windows 8 uh consulting stuff back in
the day um but yeah yeah that it was
really fun cuz it was like same kind of
thing I was building like a video player
that had like native controls over an if
frame essentially but you can call into
the JavaScript is I I bet you the API is
surprisingly similar even though that
was like oh gosh
2013 maybe something like that I have no
doubt it's it's probably virtually
identical but the nice part there is
that it is just dvis script calls to an
HTML element basically so it's like
people are like YouTube's going to come
along and then smush you in some
capacity and it's like I don't think so
but like in so far is like there's not
really anything too SM like there's no
API Keys here there's no um you know
quota limits per day it's just like
you're talking to like a physical thing
basically and saying play and pause yeah
for the video you are using the API for
no I'm not actually for the website I'm
basically just um so I get basically the
YouTube HTML um and then I do like a
crap ton of CSS and JavaScript to like
like yank out elements like um hide
elements like move elements to kind of
make it feel more Vision osy um because
it turns out so that's actually a web
view like the whole thing is except for
the um yeah yeah it turns out like if
you if you remove enough stuff like the
transparent um Vision window starts to
show through that's wild okay I I
honestly scratching away CS layers until
you see the and there's certain stuff
like if you have like the sidebar which
has your subscriptions and everything
like I'm like oh like I could take that
and just kind of move that off screen
and instead make that like a native
element and um like similar stuff with
like the search bar and whatnot like you
can like do a lot to maybe like yank out
the web elements and replace with Native
stuff um while still having like the
core thing because yeah doing the
YouTube API for that would be tricky and
so far as um funny enough they talked
about this on ATP recently the podcast
where um the YouTube like data API which
is what that would be using like has
completely nerfed itself in kind of a
Reddit way um lately where when I signed
up for it with Apollo and historically
with Apollo I got 50 million requests
per day um and they request credits or
something right exactly exactly and now
if you sign up you get 10,000 which like
if you do the math is like
0.2% of what you had um so so if I was
to build with that like You' very
quickly run into limits even just of
throughput but you also you don't get
stuff again similar to the Reddit API
you don't get stuff like recommendations
where you're like oh if you liked you
know this MKBHD video you might like
this Mr Who's The Boss video um you
would just purely get like your
subscriptions which is great and what a
lot of people use but like if you want
more recommendations and whatnot like
it's kind of to be able to Leverage The
YouTube um that's what people are
expecting if they open a YouTube app
right4 for better or worse I was
wondering with the so obviously with the
Apple TV app they've kind of got the
more immersive viewing mode where the
screen pushes like right back and
expands is that an API at all or is that
completely locked out I think that is an
API like there's a WWDC or there's maybe
a sample project um that goes over that
that I have downloaded and been may need
to open but it's I'm pretty sure you
just dock a view really far away um and
then you you basically create the
immersive environment um in the
immersive mode yeah yeah as far as I
know there's not an API though to take
any of like apples um immersive
environments and like Leverage those
unfortunately yeah it's kind of annoying
like it feels like I should be able to
take any app showing video or photos
like really I should be able to like
almost like the full screen button on
the Mac I should be able to full screen
it and then choose from the de buil-in
Apple ones cuz like the Mount Hood one
where you can see the reflections on the
water
yeah I want to watch movies on that but
like unless it's an Apple TV that's just
not an option which is really kind of
annoying yeah yeah um yeah I almost
wonder if it's like a licensing thing or
like Mountain Hood was like only
show yeah yeah I don't understand mood
itself the Rangers there are really tied
about IP yeah fires and Apple IP are
there
too they need to get oh did I disappear
for you guys no good as ever oh there we
go okay I disappeared from the feed that
was recording which is
interesting oh well um yeah they need to
get one um in the on that street where
the uh the large the small Boulder the
size of a large Boulder uh that's not M
hood is it I don't think so I'm just
saying that needs to be one of the
environments oh opportunities are yeah I
mean you I'm sure there's some AI to
build that into like stereoscopic 3D
yeah exactly yeah yeah it does feel like
the environments are going to be like
the Apple watch uh third party watch
faces where it's like if they have
nothing they're going to be like hey we
got two new environments this year and
like that can be a good 10-minute
segment to fill up some time that's fair
which I don't think I'd be mad though I
feel like I'm surprised how much I enjoy
the environments especially them the
Mount Hood one like just sitting by that
Lake just I don't know it's peaceful so
I haven't played around want that too
much so like if you took like an
existing like window and Juno or
something and and just like put it
really far back like you can't put it
far back enough I assume to make it it
like stops before the water it's like
there's like a limit from normal windows
it's weird because um you there's a
limit to how far you can push a window
back but if you just stand up and walk
forward you can push it back farther and
then you can go sit back down and it
will be that far away so theoretically
that's a handy tip you want get into the
water so could you walk into the water
of Mount Hood I think no matter what
it'll it'll start fading out if you get
out of a certain Zone in that
environment but if you fade the
environment up I think it like starts
you from that spot if that makes sense
so you're always like in the middle okay
I got you I got you yeah it's a shame
there's not even any like apis to
programmatically place like even your
own Windows like yeah I don't know it
would be cool to be like place this
slightly out their or something but it's
always yeah I do
understand that's going to be like like
it does kind of make sense that that's
at at the OS level to me yeah well it's
like I even just for iOS development or
Vision OS development rather I wish I
hate how I'll be running xcode and like
have it full screen and then it'll just
appear right in front of me um yes I'm
kind of like but I'm coding like get out
of the way like go over there um and
every single time I run the app I have
to physically move it um if you like
look over to the side you can it'll pop
up yeah that's probably but I mean
that's you know kind of annoying still
it be nice if you could at least specify
like a you know like leading trailing
top bottom kind of position relative to
your own window
yeah yeah I guess if they give you too
much control Facebook would put like
some something creepy in on your wall in
the background that you would noticed
for a week well and selfishly it's like
if you've ever done Mac development it's
like yeah have all those controls but
then it's like it's so easy to make
something wrong too like like ethically
no no no well you know you no no always
famous
for uh but just
like things behaving the way you'd
expect them to cuz like the moment that
you can break out of the
system the moment you you now are
responsible for keeping it up with every
change that they make to the system Fair
which they don't always advertise so
it's just like slight Behavior changes
now your app starts feeling off more and
more um but yeah it would be nice if the
environments themselves were something
that third parties could make them and
then others could join in but I think
just like the Apple watch it's going to
be a long time if ever that they do that
because they want those those things are
probably optimized to the nth degree um
I'm even curious how you like um if I
wanted to say fine I'll I'll do my own
like um I I guess I understand it from
like reality kit view where you you
could basically build like a sphere and
then like you know like Telegraph a
material onto it but it's like what is
the do you just license like a really
high-res like mp4 file or something like
what is the I guess the well they're 3D
they're 3D environments like they have
3D meshes you know if you shift your
head you can see around rocks the and
like I guess to answer my own thing
there are third party ones because if
you go into the Disney app or the HBO
app they have their own and those use
the same API because you can dial it in
and out just like in the regular
windowed environment only in the
immersive space so is it like a scene in
reality composer Pro that they like you
know
built like that oh interesting and then
maybe like a video file for the sky oh
okay yeah there's probably a single
sphere uh what do you call that like a
hdri um uh hdri m is that what it's
called like a 360° photo basically
that's like your Sphere for the
background but then there's a bunch of
foreground elements that are close to
you so that You' get the depth that
would be my guess yeah which I guess
yeah for
Juno since you can't like do their
immersive spaces the same way I guess
that's you would have to build your own
if you wanted to have those with some
YouTubers and have like a lonus TI tips
office background actually that would be
pretty sweet
like imagining being in
mkbhd's office see his robot camera like
in the background even like even if you
didn't go so ham as to have like you
know everything 3D built like if you
just had like a 3D photo like it would
kind of be cool um 3D photo would be
super easy yeah yeah and I I wonder if
that's the play um just just to have
You' want a floor at least though that's
yeah it would look really weird if you
didn't have that okay this is this is
giving me some idea I too if you could
go on like something like Fiverr and and
commission like a professional 3D artist
to like I wonder how much the skills are
transferable to reality composer Pro um
or or however you I would imagine they
would be I would build me something cool
yeah because yeah I imagine it's not
something you can learn in like a
weekend to what are you are you leaning
back and then leaning forward in your
chair cuz your your torso just keeps s
violently forwards and backwards like
Johnny
Bravo oh King me um I'm on like my couch
which has like um it's like an L
sectional and I'm on the L part I guess
so my legs are kind of like kicked out
and I'm like half leaning back half
leaning forward I'm a fidgeter um and
yeah this is and the nice thing about
Zoom is I could see how cursed I looked
uh but with this FaceTime stuff I can't
um let me see if supports the settings
app yeah and my my video feed for some
reason just keeps cutting out on the
zoom recording just there go I'm back
now so you know for anybody watching
that's wondering why that's happening I
I don't either no but I do know what's
happening so there's that um on it so
yeah so uh okay so we talked about you
know the development of both of these
let's talk about the launches themselves
because both of them have been really
fun to watch from the outside side I
imagine fun and maybe overwhelming from
the inside so let's start with Crouton
cuz that kind of happened first so when
the when the first uh set of reviews
came out what like three or four days
before the actual devices were released
to the public uh one of the very few
reviewers that was out there was Joanna
Stern with the Wall Street Journal and
she did this crazy cool video like she
always does where she put it on and left
it on for like 24 hours and went to his
cabin in Colorado or something and went
skiing and all the stuff but one of the
like big segments of that video the one
that I was seeing everywhere on social
media afterwards was she use your app
kuron to cook a meal and was doing the
timers and basically did this really
cool demo what what was that like one
just seeing that like when was the first
time you saw that that actually was was
in the
video uh yeah I mean it was it was all
pretty overwhelming um I think I first I
think Christian actually posted it
somewhere it was like 300 a.m. in New
Zealand I was like know Deon it's
you I don't know why I checked my phone
at 3:00 a.m. but I did um and then
didn't 10 texts I think you thought was
a you broke through my do not disturb
like I need a plane to Canada
um yeah so I uh I watched the video I
guess I should should backtrack a little
bit I um I guess like something that we
do I'm sure all of us do when we're like
going to release something we like email
a people just to let them know um you
know they've got something new coming
out and and often for me that usually
like doesn't lead anywhere so I just do
it as kind of part of the process and
then move on um but uh yeah this time
obviously uh Joanna got the email and
downloaded Crouton um which was
unexpected and and pretty sweet um and
so then I guess when the video dropped
and Christian said it was in there it's
pretty nerve-wracking before you watch
it cuz you've got like no idea how
they're going to react or like what they
might say about the experience I thought
this was the future until I used this
app yeah yeah that's
true exactly well and I guess especially
with this device um I guess like we've
talked about like it's not something
we've really had access to before the
launch so I haven't even really used
Crouton for that long um like on a
device I definitely haven't used it in a
kitchen um and so uh experiencing that
for the first time through the Wall
Street Journal
was like a lot
um but it was yeah but it was pretty it
was awesome um how positive she was
about it and it seemed like in the
review it kind of was part of what made
the device click for her in some ways
and even in some of the comments on the
video normally YouTube comments are kind
of like dire but there was a lot of
positive comments as well from people
being like Oh that timer thing actually
looks pretty sweet um I think I sent you
a text that night that was like if you
want to go full uh was it Nathan from
uh from uh Ted lasso where he like is
obsessed with going through Twitter I
was like just search Vision Pro cooking
or something on Twitter and it was just
it was literally like an unlimited
stream of comments uh that you could
have probably gotten I probably
shouldn't have sent that to you was it
was it a bad for your mental health his
hair started turning the gray color yeah
exactly yeah it's lucky I've got this
Persona to hide all the damage
um yeah I think that was definitely it
was sort of a bit of a roller coaster I
think there's a lot of people that saw
it and were like super receptive to the
idea and then uh there was also I guess
it's easier to have like a hot take of
like oh three $3,500 device to set
timers like just get a catchen timer I
think easy thing to joke about right
because it is like weird and different
and and you can see the obvious like
you're wearing a bucket on your face
using a knife like there is a story
there that is like easy to sort of make
fun of and people took that opportunity
to make jokes yeah so it was a bizarre
experience um for that day even like a
couple of days like just scrolling my
normal Twitter feed and like seeing
screenshots of like my app like just
often and yeah seeing different people's
opinions on it so it was like it was
pretty cool and it was also um when you
see like a lot of the negative ones it
can also be kind of a lot to kind of
take in um but I think I think overall
it's like it was s like obviously super
exciting and it was cool as well getting
a lot of messages from other like Indie
developers I feel like when stuff like
this happens it's almost like a win for
the whole Indie Community because when
the review comes out it's all the sort
of like the big name apps and so for
like one of us little guys Christian to
get something in there yeah yeah exactly
yeah it's always somebody like you
represent big Tech yeah yeah yeah it's
Disney uh guy from
Hells um yeah but no I think it was like
it was super cool um just to kind of um
hear from everyone and I think yeah a
chance for like every Indie developer to
kind of I guess celebrate that we kind
of push through the barrier a little bit
um such a sense of like Pride for like
other people I don't know it's weird
like it doesn't feel like we're a very
competitive industry amongst each other
like I don't know like you're just like
you're not like damn I wish that was me
you're like holy Devon's crushing
it like good for him there's definitely
some rivalries I I feel like that kind
of exist in some places but for the most
part especially in like sort of
Dev scene it's like it's just exciting
when somebody you know uh has a success
yeah yeah like and part of it is I think
it feels like we're all struggling
through the same things pretty publicly
together so it's not like we're all we
only see each other at awards season or
something you know where you're
competitive it's like most of the time
we're like man I can't figure out this
uh like for me it's like all these
obscure audio bugs and then the only
people who have also run into into that
are usually other people who make
looping ambient noise apps and they will
frequently be like oh hey I ran into
that too and I filed this feedback or oh
I tried this hack and I got it working
and once you have that interaction with
somebody it's like it's hard to ever be
mad at that person right right and these
platforms are so big that it's it's
never like you need one person to
succeed and everyone else has to fail
like I remember like I think it was like
rivan was talking about it how they were
like are you going to beat Tesla and it
was like dude there's like 1,700 car
Brands like if you just walk down the
road like and they're all most of them
are doing great like you don't need one
car brand to win like that would almost
be like everyone can do
great yeah it's interesting and yeah it
is it is really nice when it feels like
cuz I I feel like I see this with both
of you online too where it's like I feel
like if I have something written about
or whatever I feel like I have to be
self-deprecating about it like oh yeah
but it sucks whatever but when other
people are excited about it it makes it
feel like it's okay for me to be excited
about it does that make any sense yeah
know that's a good way yeah it's kind of
like a weird like I don't know I do I do
appreciate when people send me something
that I've already seen because I have
Google Alerts and stuff I do
legitimately get excited whenever I see
that right it's not like I'm just being
polite it's like a legit like oh yeah
like sometimes I'm worried that people
see me responding to multiple people
every time being excited and they're
like oh okay he's just playing this game
it's like no like I each time somebody
sends me one of those like oh you're
featured in wherever it's like another
reminder that real people see this stuff
and it's not just numbers on the
computer it never stops cool it was
pretty cool with this cuz I had like
just a couple people that I don't even
like talk to very often just like
friends like in in the real world um
that like sent me a message like hey I
just saw you in like the Wall Street
Journal I was like that's pretty crazy
it's a pretty crazy sentence
yeah yeah yeah yeah I was asking you
that the day it happened I was like I
was like is does the Wall Street Journal
have the same cuz here Wall Street
Journal is like in the same sort of
breath as New York Times or or the times
or BBC or something it's like kind of
like a institution but I didn't know if
in New Zealand if that had the same
instant recognizability like it sounds
important but people probably don't have
the same they're like oh that sounds
like an important us publication but I
don't read it um
right definely and Deon gets to go like
my buddy Joanna now all the time which
isting a little old my good friend
that's been that's been my joke because
she responded Sor today yeah yeah ohing
with
Jo and then uh so
Crouton had this really cool press but
then how did that convert into actual
sales cuz that's the weird thing about
this is well there's two pieces one is
nobody could just go buy it because the
device didn't even exist yet and two uh
almost nobody like she said the name of
the app but I've noticed it's sort of
just become shorthand that the Vision
Pro and cooking are this thing and a lot
of people don't even say the Crouton app
they just talk about it like it's just
this default app that's built in it's
been yeah I saw there was like a few top
10 like uh Vision Pro apps like lists on
Twitter and it would be like you know
like Juno d d and then it'll be like
default Timer app and a screenshot of
Crouton
what it's like this is not it's not
built in guys so it's def interesting
quite a compliment to be like on the
caliber built-in apps I mean if you want
to look at it like that I guess I guess
so but then I have to be the awkward guy
that's like oh that's me that's me I've
been trying to do that for you where I
where I see it because yeah it's really
awkward when it's yourself being like
look at me look at me yeah I just going
back to your sort of original question
it's an definitely an interesting one
because normally I guess around like iOS
update season everyone has iPhones so
when you get picked up by the PRI people
can just go to their phone and download
the app whereas even if they don't have
the new phone or the newest OS yeah and
so whereas with this it's like I think a
lot of people probably watch it and
think oh that's probably an interesting
um Vision Pro app but I'm never going to
buy one of those so like whatever and
they might not think to look at it um on
their phone and so kind of like getting
featured on the Ferrari store or
something it's an honor but like the mar
is a little smaller I will say hopefully
if if this is something that people are
like this is
the the thing that they have in their
head it's the story oh I just got a low
battery warning that's the first time
I've gotten that I have a plug right
here though two hours
baby but because because it it's a thing
that I think is sticky in people's minds
like they associate these two things
together hopefully that will mean as
people pick up new ones they immediately
look for that cooking app hopefully they
can find what that cooking app
is key the keyword yeah yeah so as long
as I don't get
overtaken no the subtitle is just that
cooking
app yeah because um there's a lot of not
a lot I definitely saw in a few places
like there' be like summaries of what
you can do on Vision Pro and it would be
like um like watch videos um move
Windows around cook is like the third
thing that you would buy this for it was
like a very yeah bizarre kind of
experience to be part of sort of the
Catalyst of that I guess idea I also
feel like I should have said at the very
start of this that I don't necessarily
recommend that you should cook with your
Vision Pro on and as if you saw the
video Joanna dismisses the warning that
says that you probably like shouldn't do
this and so um I think I'm still of the
view that with the at least this first
generation if you are going to cook with
it that's that's definitely
at your own sort of risk that's fair
that's very responsible it's like a yeah
it it feels like a preview of the future
that's kind of that's the way Joanna was
treating it which is like what you can
hope for cuz yeah you can imagine it
being treated the other way which is
like this is a horrible way to cook I
would never do this I can't see the
pepper but it's like it's not it's not
meant really to be you're not expecting
people to really be bringing this into
their lives cooking all the time it's
more like you're giving them this vision
of what what it can be like and you can
actually experience it now just in a
kind of yeah slightly subpar way because
of the pass through and stff I think as
well like the to me the operating system
itself feels really well built out and
kind of established and so the things
that are going to change over time is
going to be the hardware and and the way
that it fits on your head and things
like that and so if I can build the
whole experience now and kind of get a
hi start on that and try and I guess
build a bit of recognition with people
then when it gets to the point where it
it fits great on your face then I've
hopefully got I don't know how long it
would be but like 5 years of kind of
time where I've been able to build that
out and it's now ready to go as opposed
to waiting all of that time and then
sort of jumping on it and so it's kind
of I think there's definitely like a
long game here of like you may not use
it now but you can experience it and
hopefully get a a sense of what do you
think the hardware jump would be that
would make it like um more possible or
like feasible to to cook with
it
uh I think it would be probably the
field of view so you could see down a
bit more like if you're chopping you you
really have to look down like right down
what mean um and then um probably just I
guess maybe the clarity of the pass
through so like in Joanna's video she
talked about the color like if you're
trying to cook your food to a certain
dness it's I think going to be a bit
more challenging that's fair and like in
low light in particular it starts
getting pretty rough which if most
people that don't have super nice
kitchens it's like you're stove is
probably black and you have cabinets
right above it so that's usually a dim
area um and so being able to see we this
like giant window by by our kitchen so
it's like forus it's like really good
Vision Pro territory so during the day
well yeah that's true but New Zealand
gets 20 hours of sunlight at oh yeah
that's right that's right Alaska
permanently uh like a Lord of the Rings
uh
scene
yeah so so okay but in terms of like
sales themselves though have you cuz
Crouton already existed have you even
seen really much of an impact at all or
is it more like you know this is some
cool recognition publicly but that's
really
it uh yeah I think it's um it's
definitely had like a like a big impact
I think uh if it was if it had happened
a few years down the line where more
people had the device at the time I
think it probably would would be more
significant but it's definitely I had
pretty low expectations going in into it
cuz I I didn't actually think that like
my cooking app was going to get much
attention so to have any kind of boost
has been pretty exciting um and it's
well exceeded kind of my
expectations uh for what that would be
and I think even like not even from like
a financial perspective um there's been
at least one interaction I had with
someone where like they already knew
what Crouton was which is not an
experience that I'm I'm used to so like
I don't know if you can necessarily put
a price on some of just the recognition
that might come from it that it's now
grocer store and they were like cout guy
cout guy yeah and Kaio New Zealand yeah
no uh just on online but nor have to be
like hey you should check out Crouton
this recipe app and it's sort of now I
can sometimes at least for this week
before everyone forgets I can just say
Crouton there really is like at our
scale when a lot of your
um like if you you don't have like an
ASO team or something right so like
we're sort of earning our own uh like
users right in some capacity and a lot
of the way that most of us do it I feel
like is I'm noticing my shoulder just
keeps popping up like it's I don't know
what that's about I'm not doing that I
can tell you I thought you had music
playing and you were kind of dancing no
I mean I'm off my head of course but
like I don't know why my shoulder is
just flying up like that um anyway but
like we're if we have to acquire our own
user somehow a big way that we're doing
that is through press right through
Apple features or 9o5 or whatever or our
Twitter following or whatever so like
those are long games where it kind of
builds over time and so being known as
the XYZ person like Christian I was
listening to the latest waveform podcast
and they were like talking about the DRM
stuff and they were like yeah we texted
Christian seelig the guy who who used to
make Apollo which is what they I think
they did mention pixel files but of
course they started it with used to do
Apollo I'm just happy to be included at
all yeah but I mean it's just like you
were a person they could go to for a
random question did that interaction
help your sales unlikely right but uh
that continued relationship as being a
reliable person to reach out to that
pays dividends when you do have a big
launch and it's like you might get a
retweet or a mention in a video or
something like that right so oh exactly
I I think those types of
things they're not as like one toone
mapping to money but you know it all it
all sort of feeds into you're a member
of this community that people look to
and then that pays whenever you are
looking for
attention MH oh for sure and speaking of
attention then uh let's talk about Juno
because Juno on launch uh you didn't get
a Wall Street Journal uh video still
still hoping for Joan she snubbed
you
deep DM are all on red turns out there
is quite a lot of demand for uh for
YouTube on Vision OS because at least
last I saw you you said that like it's
already paid for itself The Vision Pro
yeah that was kind of like my super
long-term goal was like it would be cool
if it just paid for this you know
headset um but but one terab or 256 gig
I I got the yeah it depends if you yeah
if you added the accessor did you get
the tripel case well your import tax and
yeah no yeah that changes the calculus a
bit but I got the 256 gig one so I
wanted it to be as much in my favor as
possible um for sure but it would um
yeah yeah it was like I was like if they
ever paid for it that would be super
cool but like I think for me it was just
fundamentally like I just want this app
for myself and hopefully someone else
gives a crap and thankfully it seemed
like something that like a lot of people
did care about enough um and and it
always makes for a fun story when it's
something like um um you know big
cooking didn't make an app but Devon did
um and you're just like that you know
trillion dollar industry or you know
Mega Corp um wasn't able to put
something together but like you know
this guy in his apartment was able to
like that makes for a fun story too and
I think um like yeah because I think
we're all waiting for you know Martha
Stewart to come along and with like some
revolution in the VR space but I did not
know where that was going on
what is that a deep cut that I don't
know no no no I mean like in VR well in
cooking I just mean like I was you could
you could make the argument that someone
like Martha Stewart would coming and you
know blow us all away with you know her
cooking experience um but I think a lot
of
people but it said we got Devon for the
better I would argue um I don't know
this this this has lost its whales but
um
little wait was that even in this
version of the recording or was that
like one of our failed past failed
recordings I don't even know if that's a
deep cut to this episode yeah no this
this has lost any Seance of analogy but
but I just feel like you could make the
argument that you would expect like I
think unlike the iPhone 1.0 launch like
you had Epicurious and I don't even know
if they still exist but you had these
big names like coming in and being like
this is our app to do the thing um and
it seems like a lot more of like the
mega corpse had more of position of like
wait and kind of see um if it's worth
their time um which seemed a little
silly to me and like I guess a lot of us
Indies who were like well fine we'll
just build stuff we like um and and I
think yeah to a large extent a lot of
people are appreciative that someone
cared enough to build like a really cool
cooking app or a YouTube app or what
have you yeah it's interesting cuz like
yeah like even the Apple watch when that
came out there was like Twitter and
Starbucks and like all these Brands I do
think there may have been a less learned
which is a lot of them ended up kind of
abandoning that um that's true yeah
although I don't know if they built it
out of excitement or if they built it
out of apple reaching out to
partner uh you know I don't know but
it's it does feel though like this is a
much more clear yeah new platform like
especially for any kind of like media
consumption just seems probably also the
current develop like the current
environment in Tech isn't exactly
exuberance right this last year
uh in terms of like lay in terms of
there's just lots of layoffs and right
so are there a lot of people who are
just excited at Big Corp and want to
bring their app over I mean they
probably are because there's there's
still lots of people at all these places
but um that could also contribute too
but I don't know yeah it is it is
interesting is desire enough from like
the lowly employee enough to sway like
the billion dollar Corp like is there a
revenue cat app yet has
don't get don't get Deon going on that
we don't we don't have a uh we don't
have a native IOS app either it's like
our pwa I'll settle for a vision OS app
you'll settle for a vision okay we'll do
that but not have a IOS app how about
that I want like 3D
graphs this is necessary that go up and
then drop down very steeply and like the
the help docs or Charlie in spatial
video kind of walking you through it ooh
there we go I want to be a what I like
this idea because that means I need to
expense a 3D camera that's what I'm
hearing those must be expensive I 3D
cameras yeah uh I don't know like I
actually just saw you know insta 360 the
like 360
yeah they actually have one that's like
it's like a camera I'm hold oh actually
you can see my hands look at this oo it
like folds in half so there's a camera
on like either side and then that's a
360 camera right because there's a
camera pointed on either end but then
you can unfold it and then they're about
ey length apart the two lenses and then
you can shoot uh 3D video oh interesting
and is it like the same quality as like
a Go Pro or something I assume it's not
like going to blow anyone's mind yeah I
don't I that part I don't know I don't
know how it would compare to like the
iPhone right that's really the the real
comparison I guess but I guess even
something like this Mount Hood one you
don't need like like I don't know it's
well lit like you could it could
probably look decent on an iPhone even
so maybe maybe you don't need an IMAX
camera what speaking about like 360
video really quick um so I I launched a
another app on the store just day one
just sort of for for fun just like a 360
video player um cuz I noticed in the
they were publishing those lists of like
apps that were going to be available and
it didn't seem like there was going to
be any just for playing your own like
360 content um so I just thought i' I'd
put one together because it's
straight uh it's Ry r o l l i it's a bad
name because I have to spell it but um I
didn't have time to come with something
better um and it's really interesting
because yeah as far as I know there
still is no other 360 apps for playing
your own content and um what it also
seems is there's nothing for playing
your own like 180 degree content and so
I've been getting like a lot of negative
reviews from people because they
downloaded it to play their 180° content
and it doesn't work
because it it assumes any video it's got
is 360 so you wrap it in the sphere
around people right yeah I mean so I can
probably do an update to to ship it but
it's uh the harder part is when it's the
like stereoscopic 180 cuz it it's a
single video feed with both eyes and so
oh that's a thing that exists apparently
it's a big thing that exists and there's
a there's a lot of people that are
unhappy that they
can't and I'm getting the brunt of it
I'm being held responsible huh
interesting so meaning that like there's
like a video feed and it's got like the
raccoon eyes around each portion like
it's blacked out kind of essentially I
think like similar if you watch um like
Apple's 180° experiences like when you
look to the side it like goes black oh
right right okay it's almost like that
but you see both eyes with the the black
around it's more like the the IMAX or
sorry uh like well we call it Omnimax
but like the if you went to the Science
Center when you were a kid and they
played it on the big dome it's like it's
wrap around but not behind you
interesting okay yeah so I think like if
anyone wants to jump on a an opportunity
so you're not saying this is an example
of like you made this app that it's kind
of worked out you're more like uh I wish
somebody else would make this so that
people would stop sending me negative
reviews is that what you're saying
that's leave
me right there yeah I think it was one
of those things where you like naively
jump into something thinking oh just
whip this thing up and then you don't
realize that you've accidentally like
stepped into like a massive industry
that people have strong opinions about
and you're like I mean you did you made
something that there's demand for but
you didn't necessarily uh you don't have
the time to satiate that demand I guess
is what you're saying yeah or I guess
the the Deep knowledge of like one the
different video formats that exist yeah
interesting CU yeah that's that's the
tricky thing like even for Juno people
were like add like 360 or 180 degree
video and I'm like I had like cursory
knowledge that I'm pretty sure there's
like competing almost like formats is
the right word but like different
capability ways to capture that video
and I'm like I don't even know if you
managed to get the video from YouTube
how you would know like how best to
represent it like yeah if there's a way
from the teex tellw from what you
receive if it's like two eyes or like
one video stretched or like I know some
of them it's like if you open like the
mp4 file it's like a it's like a wide
video with a tall video on top of it
almost or something it's it's all very
wacky
shoulders still like bopping yeah yeah I
don't know what's going I think I my
guess is that what's going on is this
microphone cuz it's over on this side
well oh the vision I can't get my yeah
it's on this side over
here you have to hold your hand way out
in front of you to get to hand the show
up um I'm guessing it's it's something
about the microphone is messing with its
detection of my shoulder and it thinks
I'm doing something I'm not so almost
like you're like trying to close window
without
like sne sneakily doing something over
to the side it's taking you like an hour
to get it down yeah um all right so I'm
going to try and uh Land This Plane here
because this is going to already going
to be very interesting edit assuming
that we have enough actually like it's
actually still recording uh it looks
like it is um so I I think I want to
wrap this up more or less with like your
general feelings thoughts on the future
of this as like a platform for
Developers
um so Devon I'll start with you but like
I just kind of want to know like I know
you're excited about it but what is it
that you now that it's out what is it
that you're thinking this is going to
kind of turn into do you see it growing
into a vibrant platform do you think
it'll be Niche more like Apple TV or
Apple watch like where do you see things
going um yeah I mean it's pretty hard to
know this is like so many people had
like so many hot takes of like whether
it's an iPhone moment or like a Mac
moment or whatever I think like for me
it feels like there's definitely a
timeline where this at some point
replaces the mac and kind of anything
where you might like sit down and do
kind of like some focused work or like
at least like um independent work like
it's definitely not a experience at
the moment and I think it could be a
long long time before that becomes
really natural but anytime like we you
sit down and like use a computer for
something or like maybe even your TV I
could see this replacing that um in the
not too distant future like for me since
I got it um I got my nie today like last
night I just sat down and used it while
I was using my computer I used the giant
mirror display um and sat on top of the
mountain and that was like that's
already like an amazing experience on
its own and so I think anything that you
can add into that environment um like
apps and things that you could build um
be really
cool what about you Christian I think
yeah that's that's pretty hard to follow
up like it's It's tricky because it's
like I I think I partially bought it
with the hopes of finding it out myself
like where I see this going and it's
it's I feel like it's um I I haven't
quite fully formulated that opinion yet
yeah we're like three days in right like
a day and a half for Deon we need a
fully formed opinion right now go yeah I
mean I'm really trying to do is get an
audio like locked in Amber audio hot
take from you that I can hold over your
head for the next 20 years yeah you kind
of lose if you're too optimistic or too
pessimistic it's this could definitely
be something
no I think it's um I I I really like it
I think it's just really cool and I
think that's part of the reason I want
to develop for it so bad is that I was
like even if me and seven other people
are the only people who buy this um it's
just really cool to see such a different
paradigm shift in programming and
development and like building stuff um
and I find that really exciting whether
or not it goes anywhere um like that
really feels like anyone's guess like
the bulkiness of it is obviously like a
big entry um and I think just even if
like it was the most even if like the
technology from 20 years in the future
existed in this headset right now um as
it exists physically I think it would
still be a big barrier for a lot of
people to be like put on this you know
helmet basically um but as far as
development goes like I think there
could be some really cool things the
other thing I'd say is that it feels
tricky and so far as there's um with an
iPhone like especially in like 2008 when
the App Store launched like the I feel
like it was maybe I'm thinking with rose
tinted glasses but it felt easier to
program on in so far as like it was a
320 by 480 window you placed rectangles
on it and as long as those rectangles
had some semblance of beauty you were
like Off to the Races kind of and with
this there's like if you want to do
something like really really cool
there's a certain amount of like 3D like
math and like mhm um knowledge and
physics and like math and like almost
game development level knowledge you
need that is definitely um a little bit
more
um has heavier requirements I guess for
lack of a better term but it also means
like the ceiling's higher for what you
can do so it's I guess kind of yeah it's
a lot of posturing to say I don't really
know but I think it could be something I
think that's I like that that comparison
though because similar to the Mac it's
like like to make a like great Mac app
in a lot of people's meaning of that
it's like you we're talking like Final
Cut Pro or these like big complicated
ated math heavy usually creation type
apps but the thing with the mac and I
think what's been sort of brought back
more with Catalyst but I think it was
there in the olden days too is like if
it's a vibrant platform there's space
for your one-off Indies to make all
these cool little
utilities and that that's the thing
that's interesting about this compared
to like the quest or some of these
others because 3D development has
existed but I think the reason we're
excited about it is it's this is
approachable because it's it's got Swift
UI it's got UI kit it's got like uh it's
doing a lot of the hard stuff for you
we're not doing that much complicated
game 3D development yet we're still
making something that takes advantage of
the spatial nature of the
platform until you go into immersive
mode and then it's like suddenly gets a
little mad it's yes right but that's the
thing it's kind of like there's tears
that work their way out right for sure
yeah I think as well like I've seen a
lot of um I think points of view of uh
cuz like when everyone started sort of I
guess posting what they've been working
on a lot of people's apps were um like
coming from iPad and so that I guess
mostly 2D and there was I saw a few
people that sort of thought that that
was disappointing and like I want more
like 3D stuff and like none of this iPad
stuff which I I think is fair in some
regards but I feel like just because we
can now represent 3D objects on this
platform doesn't mean everything should
be 3D like the window in itself is
actually 3D because it exists within
your room and so there's utility to that
already I guess like with the Tim is
right like it's just a window I'm not
doing anything special with that but
there's utility inherent in it in the
way that it exists in the room and so I
don't think that there needs to be a
push that like all of a sudden all of
our buttons need to be these big like 3D
objects CU I think I think there should
be a mix and it's awesome that we have a
platform now where you can actually mix
those things in different apps and not
be limited to one but I I don't think
I'd want to see a big shift to where
like everything is now
three-dimensional that makes sense yeah
that would be a little more mentally
taxing and and I think what with that
disappointment too like what a lot of
maybe people who aren't developers like
us don't realize that so much of the
like oh I did want 3D stuff and it's
like that stuff is like trickier in the
tools we had prior to the Vision Pro
launching like the simulator is like
just not even out of necessarily any um
lack of effort by but just like having a
2d window on your Mac completely emulate
like a 3D development environment where
you're placing like cues objects
everywhere yeah like it it's really hard
to do so I think if anything it's like
now that it's out you know and more
people's hands outside of just the lucky
few who got developer kits like now
might be the chance we start to see
people actually developing like the cool
3D applications so maybe just wait a
little
bit be patient yeah yeah we're just
we're just on like not even week one
really to your to your I guess to answer
my own question then at the beginning
like future of the platform whatever
like I think I'm sort of similar to you
Christian in the sense that like it's
just cool like it's fun like the thing I
so I was a lot more bearish kind of on
it as
a platform like is this really going to
be a thing that takes off is bear the
good one or the bad bear is the bad so
the way you remember it is uh the statue
of the bear fighting the bull the bull
is like bringing his horns up statue of
a bear fighting a bull yeah in Wall
Street what came first the phrase or the
statue I think the statue is first I
could be wrong or maybe it was just like
a common image of I think the statue was
there first but yeah there I've seen
I've seen the bull so there's a I think
there's a bear in a bull or is it just
the bull I thought it was just a I feel
like I'd remember a bear fighting
something well either way the mental
image I think is that it's a bear
fighting a ball maybe it's just a bull
because it's like it's the positive
version Googled it and it's like a I can
see why you would think it's a bull
facing a little
girl um and I can see it looks like it's
like a little girl standing like with
her hands on her hips like standing up
to the bulll and I can see how you
mistake a little girl for an adult
grizzly bear um yeah they're pretty much
the same okay but the idea think is that
the bull is attacking up with his horns
and the bear is coming down on the and
you are and you are a bear which is I
was more bearish I was I was more
negative see this is why it's a good
phrase because it requires so much
mental load to talk to stock Brokers
only or something right I think yeah
you're right you're
right anyway I I was and maybe am more
at before all this I actually wrote like
a blog post that I didn't talk about cuz
I I wasn't necessarily proud of it but I
just wanted to write up like my thoughts
before I went into the uh into the lab
because I knew after that I couldn't say
anything cuz I just wanted like a note
like an archive of what I thought before
trying it yeah exactly and like my
feelings are somewhat similar which is
like it's it's a platform
that's difficulty to use is very high
because you're putting something on your
head true and I I don't see a version of
the like glasses like true glasses
happening in
a very long time just from a technology
standpoint so like iterations on this
you know much better version of this but
still iterations of a VR thing is kind
of what I'm imagining and it's like I
have a hard time seeing
that take off as a like super commonly
used thing because there's so much load
in putting it on it's closer to a Mac
Pro than an iPhone in terms of like like
an iPhone like an Apple Watch doesn't
have to be nearly as high util because
it's so easy to use it's just on your
wrist and then a phone is like one step
up from that your MacBook Air is one
step up from that and then like a
desktop computer it has to have a whole
bunch of utility because it's way harder
to use you have to sit at a desk blah
blah blah this to me feels like it's
closer to the Mac Pro end of things than
the Apple watch end because of the
difficulty of this because it's like a
pain to put on but I will say like so
you're you'd be pretty piggish on like
an apple jumpsuit
then
I don't even I don't know what this
means
uh
sure maybe I guess I don't know but
anyway so like uh
the
it the thing that it has to overcome is
is you putting it on keeping it charged
and being this thing that you regularly
put on your head and it has to provide
enough utility to make that worth it I
will say in this first weekend of having
it
um maybe just because it's new but I
found it's it actually reminds me
weirdly of the iPad where I like using
it and I want to keep using it and then
I just kind of like sit in there like
what am I doing in here like it's
especially because it's so hard to type
it's like it's nice for FaceTime I
FaceTime with a bunch of people and I
actually really like that experience uh
it's nice for the like mac mirroring
personally I
I don't know if it's just my eyes but
like I find it a little bit harder to
use compared to my Mac laptop even even
though the screen's way bigger um but it
is kind of nice especially when sitting
on the couch or something like that but
in terms of like sitting here making it
part of my regular workflow it's kind of
like weird I I haven't found something
where I'm like this is so much better
not cooler but better there's lots of
things that are cooler but that utility
wears off and and so I'm just not sure
but it's but the thing that's like the
iPad is interesting because if it is
that compelling and fun to use people
will like force workflows into it which
help keep it kind of alive and vibrant
and then maybe the technology kind of
catches up in terms of comfort and all
of that so I'm more excited about it
than I was initially that's good okay
but it's hard you know in terms of like
predicting will this be a major platform
like
the iPhone's a bad example I think the
Mac is a more appropriate example just
because it took the Mac a decade or so
to get to like really mainstream Mass
market right it wasn't like it was a big
deal when it first came out but it
wasn't uh it didn't keep the company
afloat for a very long time right right
um so I don't know I don't know but it
also didn't have the marketing and just
platform connecting oomph that Apple has
now and yeah much less of a statement
piece like you see somebody in one of
these and it's kind of like holy crap
yeah that's hard to ignore um right like
for yeah For Better or Worse um what are
your kids like when you wear it are they
kind of like oh Dad's doing his thing
yeah I E today what's that uh like I had
this moment yesterday cuz I I um came
home with it opened it and my son was
asleep in in Bard while I was using it
um and I was kind of planning of like
not really letting them them like see it
for a bit just cuz it's a bit odd and
also didn't want them to like break it
um but I was just sort of standing in
the lounge I can't what I was doing and
then he came in from his nap and just
kind of stared at me and I stared back
at him with my giant robot face and I
could see like this look of Terror you
can see
[Laughter]
the is he okay now I I think well he
hasn't talked
to fact I haven't seen
him
no mine mine have tried it like they had
and they we had a quest or have a quest
too and they've tried that before too
and it felt similar to that where we're
like everybody's trying it on and we're
airplane to the TV and it's like a fun
but that doesn't feel like the future of
computing that's like it's a fun uh
amusement park ride or whatever right
right um but like I will say it does
feel like you can just be in a space
with somebody and talk to them it's not
horrible for that
um but it's still it's still weird I
I'll say the one that really surprised
me is my dog makes eye contact with me
still like normal interesting like I I I
wasn't sure what to expect there but he
just looks right at my eyes I don't know
how much of dogs are looking at your
eyes or they're like evolutionarily like
they know to look at people's faces you
know what I mean like they're actually
looking for your fangs or something um
but he just looks right at me just like
normal and I talk to him like he hasn't
reacted weird at all to it I think the
the glass area in the front being so
different from the quest though that
that like it must help there like I
remember when I put the quest on and my
girlfriend said something to me and I
and I turned to her and like because I
had the pass to run and I just
immediately like rubber neck to her and
answered her question she like did not
like that because I think she assumed I
was in like a world separate from hers
and that I was completely cognizant of
um but where this I think it's a little
bit more obvious that you're you're
aware of the your surroundings even just
the Black versus the white cuz the white
especially if you're like white
complected skin it almost is like you're
faceless like in a weird blindfold on or
something yeah yeah whereas the black
almost is like goggles like right right
yeah yeah there's some level of
sunglasses where you can see through
them still yeah yeah um for sure yeah
all right well um I will wrap this up
and hopefully be able to edit this in
the next three or four months we'll see
how recoverable this is but this was
like super fun it's always fun to just
hang out with you guys anyway so yeah no
this is awesome apprciate you sitting
here debugging FaceTime with me for
hours yeah so uh Devin where can people
find you and all of your
apps uh yeah I'm on all all of the
current social platforms I
think there might be a new one
tomorrow what's your
Noster okay I'm not on all of them I
take it back I'm
on I'm on X and madon uh my is just me
div um and you can find um my app as the
default Timer app on Vision
Pro that's Crouton uh the cooking app or
rly r o l l i for the 360 app which I'll
say if you have a 360 camera uh it is
actually really fun uh to to try those
out and kind of like float around in a
space if you've captured those
before yeah I'm definitely going to
check it out um I just camera that can
do it yeah yeah and then Kristen uh
where can people find find you and
Apollo
yeah it's like yeah your local Cemetery
um you can find me um I'm Christian SE
like pretty much yeah I'm unfortunately
still on Twitter I'm on Mastadon as well
um uh I think I'm on threads Blue Sky
probably the um yeah just SP everywhere
all right cool well thank you both again
uh chance I'll see you see you some
other time yeah how do I wrap the show
up everything is weird yeah no it's
we'll see you when we see
you thanks for listening if you'd like
to discuss the show you can find me on
Twitter maedon threads or whatever the
social media app of the day is at
Charlie M chapman. me we'd really
appreciate a rating or review on your
podcast app of choice and you can find
show notes and more at launched FM
[Music]
.c